/*IAN1011*/
<head type=main> Illustrated Arctic News </head>
<head type= sub> N<hi rend= "super">o</hi> 1 "TUTO ET SINE METU" October 31. 1850.</head>
<p>[graphic of a man on his head with legs spread shaped like a Y]es! <hi rend= underline>The Illustrated Arctic News!</hi></p>
<p>Shake thy head as thous wilt good friend- such we intend to be the name of our publication_an aspiring one, no doubt; yet, he that laketh ambition, lacketh all_ and provided our motive be good, what care we for the result.-</p>
<p>"Thy object friend?" demands Matter of Fact_ Amusement, good dame, is our reply_ We seek to attain no more that we profess_ to reliece the monotony of sunless days_to show to all, that fun + [and] good fellowship, may exist by <hi rend= "underline">Purser's</hi> Moon-light_ that Romance can survive the dense atmosphere of twenty four to the pound_ that in the desolation of Land +[and] Ice around us, the gentle lily Wisdom, can still be outted [maybe?]_ wither in the con-templation of the ruins of an old World, or in the strange, + [and] ever changing phenomena of nature, bywhich we are surrounded;_ and lastly, to keep alive in all our hearts, those sweet recollections ternere and heace, which bind us to our Homes, our Country, and our Friends.-</p>
<p>And come what will, we shall not travail in cain, if Mirth should be lured to spend a winter on the floe, or that grovelling fellow Care, be banished from our Arctic Circle.</p>
<p>In conclusion, we have only to add, that as the sucess of the <hi rend= underline>"Illustrated Arctic News"</hi>, must necessarily sepend on the vountary contributions of our readers, we trust that for want of support, it will not become <cb n="2"/> [graphic of a man at a desk with a large W on the wall]E gladly avail ourselces of the kindness of an anonymous correspondent who had forwarded us copies of a series of letters, written by himself to his Friends,_ and to a fair creature, who is, as he assures us_ all soul!_</p>
<p>We presume, our friend, has the young lady's heart in safe keeping.</p>
<floatingText><head>Letter N<hi rend="super">o</hi> 1.</head>
    <opener>My Dear Father,</opener>
    <body><p>We are about to sail for the shores of Lancaster Sound, and to turn our backs on the covilized World for some years;_ Already has our escape from Shipwreck, +[and] destruction been almost miraculous!_ Imagine three Ice-bergs, as big as St Pauls! tilting at each other, and we in our poor Vessels!_ Two Captain's Cox-swains, + [and] three Quarter Masters, became grey-headed en that terrible night! &amp; me it made a wiser, &amp; I trust, a better man_ recalling to my recollection the fact that a small Bill, about £36, is still owing to Looney in Regent Street, ..... for some Cigars, (you remember I told you the Commodore insisted on our smoking) for which Bamble will send you the amount, about Christmas day.</p>
        <p>The Officer of my Watch is delighted with my zeal &amp; activity; and appears to enjoy mu company, and Cigars_ I think the Captain regrets he cannot at once promote me; and I'm firmly resolved that the name of ----------------, shall become memorable in the annals of the Arctic Ocean <pb/></p>
        <p>The Gold Repeaters you so kindly gave me, I, on second thoughts could not think of bringing with me_ <hi rend="underline">Fastman</hi>, who keeps the "Bargue" at Woolwich, presented one with asmall [this is weird] Account, at a moment the safety of the ship, required me not to lave the deck, &amp; I therefore gave him the Watch to keep until you called and settled his demand_ The "Brandies" were for the Poliecemen, whom we were obliged to concibiate, and they drink horribly.</p>
        <p>To work is mt sole delight, and being on double pay, I feel called on for double exertion._ I sometimes however accompany a few friends on a shooting ecvursion, in order to study &amp; obtain specimens of Natural History._</p>
        <p>By the bye, the Bill for £12, drawn at the Orkneys, was expended in Oil &amp; Candles, to enable me to read upon carious important sub-jects during the Winter months._</p>
        <p>I am grieved to saym that civili-zation, has made but little progress, among the benighted inhabitants of these regions, Alas! their minds are as barren as the hills which now surround us.</p>
        <p>I had almost forgotten to inform you, that the Landlady of the Ship &amp; Tower and M<hi rend="superscript">rs</hi>Ethelredffrom whom my frugal supper of Potatoes &amp; Oysters, was nightly obtained/ refused to recieve payment unkil Michaelmas, &amp in my absence will you oblige me, but letting you Agent square the tally?</p>
        <p>Every blessing attend you, if i fall, remem-ber it is in a good cause.</p>
        <fig></fig>
        <p>P.S._ Kilbee and Rails, the wretches, never sent their Accounts in, I do not wish them to excrate my memory.</p>
        <p>The Bergs are breaking in all directions, Hands save Ship!!_ Good Bye_</p>
    </body>
</floatingText>
<fig></fig>
<div type="weather">
    <head>STATE OF THE WEATHER</head> 
    <p>The waether for the last few days, has been markably mild and dry. We are happy to <indesipherable/> our Cheroots are in the same condition. <cb/> </p>
</div>
<graphic>A picture of graves in the mountains.</graphic>
<div type="article">
    <head>SEAMENS GRAVES_BEECHEY ISLAND.</head>
    <p>A lonely hour spent bedside the Tombs on Beechy Island, recalled to our recollection the many lands, in which we had met similar traces of out Countrymen's wanderings_ Alas! in this case the associations were indeed sad, and melan-choly; for those simple head boards, are the sole records left of the sojourn &amp; departure of those we seek_ and in this scene they but mark the first stage of the perilous voyage of the missing Explorers towards renown.</p>
    <p>The day we chose for our visit, was dark, and gloomy;_ with sudden gusts of wind sweeping over land &amp; ice, hiding every distant object from our view in snow drift_ and as we surmounted the point of land, and lost sight of our Vessles, all was as dreary and lonely, as the most saddened heart could wish.</p>
    <p>Before us lay the Bay, on whose lone bosom Franklin's Squadron once had rose_ <hi rend="underline">here,</hi> was the sire if the ruined observatory, where science had laboured with honest zeal, and ambition, <hi rend="underline">there,</hi> the deserted mound, on which once has stood the workshop, alive with life, and racy joke_ whilst the little Garden at our feet, long since fallen to decay evinced, that even the poor shivering Flora of the North, had her votaries in that "Galliant Compagnee";_ It was farther down the slope that the three dark beacons stood, which were placed over the remains of those who fell victims to the rigour of an Arctic Winter. What a tale of regret and kindly feeling, was told by the neatly finished head board!_ all replete with interest.</p>
    <p>Yet apart from refret, for the<pb/> departed, and anxiety for the missing, there was nothing unusually terrible in such a last resting place from the fevered labors of this life_ here at any rate, the <indesipherable>cairn</indesipherable>, which marks one's resting place, stands a monument of human enterprise of British perserverance!_</p>
    <p>What the carved stone of the Scandana-vian Viking is to the modern antiguary_ so shall in future ages be, the humble Toombstone of the English Seaman_ proods in both alike of hardihood, &amp; energy.</p>
    <graphic>dividing line</graphic>
    <p>The following particulars were<cb/> copied from the head boards of the graves on Beechy Island.</p>
</div>