<div>
<div>
    <figure>Heading of paper wuth an images of an arctic skyline. Boats of varrying type and size in the ocean mostly toward the icey terrian in the background. Beams of sunlight radiate from the center of the sky. At the top of the banner image is the word 'THE'. Below the image are the words 'ILLUSTRATED ARCTIC NEWS.' in a font resumbling sculpted snow. There is a dividing line underwhich is written <p>N<hi rend="superscript">o</hi> 1  "TUTO ET SINE METU."   OCTOBER 31, 1850.</p></figure>
</div>
<div type="article">
  <figure>Person on his head with arms crossed and legs opened in the shape of a 'Y'.</figure>ES! <hi rend="unerline">The Illustrated Arctic News!</hi>Shake thy head as thou wilt goof friend_ such we intend to be the name of our publication_ an sspiring one, no doubt; yet, he that lacketh ambition, lacketh all_ and provided our motive be good, what care we for the result.
    <p>"Thy object friend?" demands Matter of Fact_ Amusement, good dame, is our reply_ We seek to attain no more than we profess_ to relieve the monotony of sunless days_ to show to all, that fun + good fellowship, may exist by <hi rend="underline">Pursers'</hi> Moon-light_ that Romance can survive the dense atmosphere of "twenty four" to the pount_ that in the desolation of Land + Ice around us, the gentle lily Wisdom, can still be outlled_ either in the contemplation of the ruins of an old World, or in the strange, + ever changing phenomena of Nature, by which we are surrounded;_ and lastly, to keep alive in all our hearts, those sweet recollections "tendere and treave", which bind us to our Homes, our Country, and our Friends._</p>
    <p>And come what will, we shall not reavail in vain, if Mirth should be lured to spend a winter on the floe, or that grovelling fellow Care, be banished from our Arctic Circle.</p>
    <p>In conclusion, we have only to add that as the success of the <hi rend="underline">"Illustrated Arctic News"</hi>, must necessarily depend on the voluntary contributions of our readers, we trust that for want of support, it will not become <figure>Small image of a ship on rough seas with the caption "Stationary".</figure></p><cb/>
</div>
<div type="framearticle">
    <p><figure>Image of man in black coat and bowler hat at a desk writing with a feather quill. On the left an open book and a wine bottle, on the right a candle and a cup half full of dark fluid with a spoon in it. On the dark walls is the shape of a 'W'.</figure>E gladly avail ourselves of the kindness of an anonymous correspondent, who has forwarded us copies of a series of leters, written by himself to his Friends,_ and to a fair creative, who is, as he assures us_ "all soul!"_</p>
    <p>We presume, our friend, has the young lady's heart in safe keeping.</p>
</div>
<div type="letters">
    <figure> Dividing line.</figure>
    <head>LETTER N<hi rend="superscript">O</hi> 1.</head>
    <floatingText>
        <body>
            <opener>Dear Father,</opener>
            <p>We are about to sail for the shores of Lancaster Sound, and to turn our backs on the civilized World for some years;_ Already has our escape from Shipwreck, + destruction been almost miraculous!_ Imagine three Icebergs, as big as S<hi renf="superscript">t</hi> Pauls! tilting at each other, and we in our poor Vessels!_ Two Capatin's Coxswains, + three Quarter Masters, became grey-headed men that terrible night! &amp; me it made a wiser, + I trust, a better man_ recalling to my recollection the fact that a small Bill , about £36, is still owing to Looney in Regent Street; <!-- maybe a redacted name? !--> for some Cigars, (you remember I told you the Commodore insisted on our smoking) for which Bamble will send you the amount, about Christmas day.</p>
            <p>The Officer of my Watch is delighted with my zeal + activity; and appears to enjoy my company, and Cigars_ I think the Captain regrets he cannot at once promote me; and I'm firmly resolved that the name of <!-- redcated !-->, shall become memorable in the annals of the Arctic Ocean<pb/></p>
            <p>The Gold Repeater you so kindly gave me, I, on second thoughts could not think og bringing with me_ <hi rend="underline">Fastman,</hi>who keeps the "Bargue" at Woolwich, persented me with a small Account, at a moment the safety of the ship, requiredme not to leave the deck, + I therefore gave him the Watch to keep until you called and settled his demans_ The "Brandies" wer for the Polievemen, whom we were obliged to conciliate, and they brink horribly.</p>
            <p>To work is my sole delight, and being on double pay, I feel called on for double exertion._ I sometimes however accompany a few friends on a shooting excursion, in order to study + obtain specimens of Natural History._</p>
            <p>By the bye, the Bill for £12, draen at the Orkneys, was expended in Oil + Candles, to enable me to read upon various important subjects during the Winter months._</p>
            <p>I am grieved to say, that civilization, has made but little progress, among the benighted inhabitants of these regions, Alas! their minds are as barren as the hilla which now surround us.</p>
            <p>I had slmost forgotten to inform you, that the Lnadlady of the "Ship + Tower" and M<hi rend="superscript">re</hi> Ethelredlfrom whom my frugal supper of Potatoes + Oysters, was nightly abtained/ refused to revieve payment unlil Muchaelma, + in my absence will you oblige me, by letting your Agent square the tally?</p>
            <p>Every blessing attend you, if I fall, remember it is in a good cause.</p>
            <p>* * * * *</p>
            <p>P.S._ Kilbee and Rails, the wretches, never sent their Accounts in, I do not wish them to execrate my memory.</p>
            <p>The Bergs are breaking in all directions, Hands save Ship!!_ Good Bye_</p>
            <figure>Dividing line.</figure>
        </body>
    </floatingText>
</div>
<div>
    <head>STATE OF THE WEATHER.</head>
    <p>The weather for the last few days, has been markably mild and dry. We are happy to <!-- had to look at the more recent pictures because the word was cut off !--> say our Cheroots are in the same condition.</p><cb/>
</div>
<div><figure>Three raised graves with headstones in the foreground and a snowy mountain in the background.</figure>
    <head>SEAMENS GRAVES_ BEECHEY ISLAND.</head>
    <p>A lonely hour spent beside the Tombs on Beechy Island, recalled to our recollection the many lands, in which we had met similar traces of our Countrymrn's wanderings_ Alas! in this case the associations were indeed sad, an melancholy; for those simple head boards, are the sole records left of the sojourn + departure of those we seek_ and in this scene they but mark the first stage of the perilous voyage of the missing Explorers towards renown.</p>
    <p>The day we chose for our own visit, was dark, and gloomy;_ with sudden gusts of wind sweeping over land + ice, hiding every distant object from our view in snow drift_ and as we surmounted the point of land, and lost signt of our Vessles, all was dreary and lonely, as the most saddened heart could wish.</p>
    <p>Before us lay the Bay, on whose lone bosom Franklin's Squadron once had rode_ <hi rend="underline">here,</hi> was the site of the ruined  observatory, where science had laboured with honest zeal, and ambition, <hi rend="underline">there,</hi> the deserted mound, on which once had stood the workshop, alive with life, and racy joke_ whilst the little Garden at our feet, long since fallen to decay, evinced, that even the poor shivering Flora of the North had had her votaries in that "Galliant Compagnie";_ It was farther down the slope that the three dark beacons stood, which were placed over the remains of those who fell victims to the rigour of an Arctic Winter. What a tale of regret and Kindly feeling, was told by the neatly finished head board!_ all replete with interest.</p>
    <p>Yet apart from regret, for the <pb/>departed, and anxiety for the missing, there was nothing unusually terrible in such a last resting place from the fevered labours of this life_ here at any rate, the cairn, which marks one's resting place, stands a monument of human enterprise! o British perseverance!_</p>
    <p>What the carved stone of the Scandanavian Viking is to the modern antiquary_ so shall in future ages be, the humble Tombstone of the English Seaman_ proofs in both alike of hardihoos, + energy.</p>
    <figure>Line.</figure>
    <p>The following particulars were<cb/> copied from the head boards of the graves on Beechey Island.</p>
    <lg><l>Sacred</l>
        <l>to the</l>
        <l>Memory of</l>
        <l>John Hartnell</l>
        <l>A.B. of H.M.S.</l>
        <l>Erebus.</l>
        <l>died Janr <!-- this might be a superscript, honestly I'm not sure !--> 4<hi rend="superscript">th</hi> 1846.</l>
        <l>aged 25 years</l>
        <l>Haggai_ C.I _V.1.<!-- so these could be ones or ls, but i can't tell. Though I do think they should be the same. !--></l>
        <l>'Thus saith the Lord of Hosts'</l>
        <l>'Consider your ways'</l>
    </lg>
        <l>Sacred</l>
        <l>to the</l>
        <l>Memory of</l>
        <l>W. Braine. R.M.</l>
        <l>H.M.S. Erbus.</l>
        <l>died April 3<hi rend="superscript">rd</hi>/46.</l>
        <l>32 years.</l>
        <figure>Line.</figure>
        <l>'Choose you this day, whom</l>
        <l>ye will serve'</l>
        <l>Joshua C 24 part of 15<hi rend="superscript">th</hi> verse</l>
    <lg>
    </lg>
    <lg>
        <l>Sacred</l>
        <l>to</l>
        <l>the memory of</l>
        <l>John Torrington,</l>
        <l>who departed</l>
        <l>this</l>
        <l>life, January 1<hi rend="superscript">st</hi></l>
        <l>A.D. 1846.</l>
        <l>on board of</l>
        <l>H.M.S. Terror,</l>
        <l>aged 20 years.</l>
    </lg>
</div>
<div>
    <figure>Banner image of two large ships and a smaller rowboat in the middle of a broken up ice floe. Caption: UNION BAY _ BEECHEY ISLAND.</figure>
    <figure>Crown with two Brirish flags crossed at the top, encircled in laurels.</figure>
    <head type="main">SONGS OF THE NORTH.</head>
    <head type="sub">Dedicated to M<hi rend="superscript">rs</hi> Austin,</head>
    <head type="sub">By the Authors.</head>
    <figure>Dividing line.</figure>
    <head type="sub">N<hi rend="superscript">o</hi>1._The Traveller's Evening Song,</head>
    <lg>
        <l>When last we saw out Shipmates kind,</l>
        <l>And heard their farewell greeting,</l>
        <l>Though loath to leave them all behind,</l>
        <l>We hope a joyful meeting;</l>
        <l>And trust to see our Ship once more,</l>
        <l>Thato'er the Ocean bore us;</l>
        <l>And cheer the Friends, who now deplore,</l>
        <l>The fate of those before us.</l>
    </lg>
    <lg>
        <l>When the joys of home we think,</l>
        <l>One lovely face comes cheering,</l>
        <l>A sweet voice whispers_ do not shrink!</l>
        <l>The absent you are nearing!</l>
        <l>With hope renewed, then on we go,</l>
        <l>England must not blush for us!</l>
        <l>And with fresh vigour cross the floe,</l>
        <l>In Search of those before us.</l>
    </lg>
    <lg>
        <l>And whilst this dreary waste we roam,</l>
        <l>May conscience oft' remind us,</l>
        <l>What rapture will be felt at home,</l>
        <l>By those we've left behind us;</l>
        <l>If with sucess our hopese are crown'd,</l>
        <l>And fortune should restore us,</l>
        <l>To Britain's shore, with those we've found,</l>
        <l>Our Comrades gone before us.</l>
    </lg>
    <signed>G.F. M<hi rend="superscript">c</hi> D.</signed><pb/>
</div>
<div>
    <figure>Banner image of ships in ice with stairs of ice blocks leading up to the largest ship in the foreground. Figure in foreground waves to retreating figures of men pulling sleads with suppies. Other ships with men pulling sleads can be seen in the background.</figure>
    <head type="main">DEPARTURE OF THE TRAVELLING PARTIES.</head>
    <head type="sub">Editors Portfolio.</head>
    <figure>Illuminated letter. Little boy in a clown/circus performer costume with a stick and hoop. The hoop formes the letter 'O'.</figure>
    <p>N the morning of the 2<hi rend="superscript">nd</hi> Jns<hi rend="superscript">t</hi> Lieut<hi rend="superscript">t</hi> Aldrich, with six men, and one Sledge, left for Simerville Island, with a view to form a depot towards Cape Walker_ Lieut<hi rend="superscript">t</hi> M<hi rend="superscript">c</hi>Clintock + D<hi rend="superscript">r</hi>Bradford, with twelve men + four Sledges, started at the smae time, in order to deposit provisions, as ar as possible on the line of route to Melville Island._</p>
    <p>M<hi rend="superscript">r</hi>Cheyne with 1 Sledge, + six men, as a fatigue party, accompanied the above Officers to assist in drawing the Sledges a day's journey_</p>
    <p>Lieut<hi rend="superscript">t</hi>Mecham + M<hi rend="superscript">r</hi>Ede, with a lightly equipped party, finishes the Examination of the South Coast of Cornwallis Isl<hi rend="superscript">d</hi> between Cape Hotham + Martyrs.</p>
    <p>Heartily did we give them a Sailors' God Speed! in cheers as in the lighest possible spirits, they commenced thier laborious march.</p>
    <figure>Dividing line.</figure><!-- I don't know if this should be a new div or if it is technically a part of the same article -->
    <p>We gladly insert the following extracts, from a Skeleton journal, kept by an Officer during his absence with one of the late Travelling parties. <!-- By late does he mean dead? Is this from his crew or the one they are looking for? --></p>
    <figure>Dividing line.</figure>
    <p>Oct<hi rend="superscript">r</hi> 2<hi rend="superscript">nd</hi>_7 A.M._ Having stowed <!-- Using the Hamilton version starting here.  --> Sledges with pemmician, pork, and pipes, Belly_ with Tea and Tommy_ left the Ship,_ Crew Cheered_ Too full_ feelings I mean_ to return the Compliment.<!-- End use of Hamilton copy. --></p>
    <p>6 P.M._ Stick Tent, and a light, commenced smoking_ Baccy spoilt by Boreas_ Took Tea, and turned in, thought of the Time when I revelled in Tea, Toast, Tarts, + Testament, or Shetty, Scandal, Songs, + Sentiment. Took to the bottle + bag_ Slept + Snored as usual; although Cold + Comforless_ Ther<!-- There is a superscript in here that I cant really read, it could be an r or a N --> 10°</p>
    <p>11 P.M._ Dreaming of Dolly_ Water made in_ we made off_ thought of Childhood's Copyslip, referring to "Time + Tide"._</p>
    <p>Oct<hi rend="superscript">r</hi>3<hi rend="superscript">rd</hi>_ Awoke, horribly hot_ Ther-17° Coca and Conversation_ Had a Slide and smoke_ Noon, dined_ digested ditto by dragging.</p>
    <figure>Dividing line.</figure>
    <p>The M.S.S. here ceases in consequence of the Ink having become solid, an evil which might have been remedied, had not the pencils been already used for fuel._</p>
    <figure>Dividing line.</figure>
</div>
<div>
    <head>CONSOLATION TO A CAPTIVE FOX.</head>
    <figure>A horse looking fox chained to a post looking towards the words alinged next to it.</figure>
    <lg>
        <l>Poor Reynard! like thy reputation,</l>
        <l>Thy life, is now, nit worth a fig_</l>
        <l>Thou art collar'd_at their next Collation,</l>
        <l>They'll serve thee like a collar'd Pig._</l>
    </lg><pb/>
</div> 
<div>
    <head>ARCTIC THEATRICALS.</head>
    <figure>Illuminated letter. Woman sitting at a small table by a fire with a tea set before her. On the fire is a kettle blowing a billowing cloud of steam within which there is the letter 'T'.</figure>
    <p>HE Intrepid Royal Saloon was on Thursday honored with the presence of the principal personages in these realms.</p>
    <p>The performances consisted of a series of songs, sung by accomplished Vocalists, and a pathetic recitation or two, so admirably delivered, as to cause all the handkerchiefs to be put in requisition, that had not previously been stolen by some loose characters at the door, who had succeeded in gaining admittance, nothwithstanding the vigilance of our active police force_ All the arrangements were admirably carried out, and the company separated at a late houe, highly gratified with their evening's amusement_ We hope the good example thus shown, will be followed by the other Ships of the Arctic Squadron, and although a "floe" exists between us, we shall always be happt to contribute our mite towards forwarding such a desirable object._</p>
    <figure>Dividing line.</figure>
</div>
<div>
    <figure>Large dividing image. A man in a hammock is dreaming of dinners, balls, and horse rides. Another man in a coat and hat, carrying a lantern seems to be there to awaken the dreaming man likely named green as the trunk below the hammock says Green.</figure>
    <caption>THE DREAM _ MIDNIGHT _ MIDDLE WATCH.</caption>
    <caption>Quarter Master_ "It's 12 o'Clock Sir" _ blowing hard and snowing heavily.</caption>
</div>
<div>
    <head>LITERATURE.</head>
    <head>The Arctic Periodicals;_</head>
    <figure>Dividing line.</figure>
    <p>We have perused with great interest the three numbers of a charming periodical;_"The Aurora Borealis" conducted by the Oficers of Assistance + Itrepid._ W cannot speak too highly of its contents, which are at once amusing + instructive, and we look forward with pleasure to its next appearance.</p>
    <p><!-- Start using the Hamilton copy here for the cut off text. --> Like its grat namesake, which during the dark rigours of an Arctic Winter,_ illumines with lustrous rays of light, the dreary waste of these inhospitable regions, so our cotemporaty, with its brilliant corruscations of wit and pointed pencillings, will enliven the dull solitude of our winter, and under its benign influence dispel dark despondency from our minds.</p>
    <figure>Dividing line.</figure><!-- End using the Hamilton copy here. I got a little carried away. -->
</div>
<div>
    <head>LAURA GLAUCUS, LEAVES THE "RESOLUTE" AND DIES ON BOARD THE "ASSISTANCE".</head>
    <lg>
        <l>Laura Glaucus why dids't roam_</l>
        <l>And dies midst strangers at a distance_</l>
        <l>Alas! why not remain at home_</l>
        <l>And earn thy bread without Assistance.</l>
    </lg><pb/>
</div>
<div>
    <head>PARODY ON THE LEGACY.</head>
    <figure>In the foreground there is a man leaning down, taking things out of a box marked with what is likely a name. Behind him is a tent where a face is peeking out of the flap. Behind the tent is a shadowy figure.</figure>
    <lg>
        <l>When in a Tent, on my back I recline,</l>
        <l>I sign, and with hunger exclaim Oh dear!</l>
        <l>I'm obliged to forego both beer, and wine,</l>
        <l>And <hi rend="underline">luxurie</hi> all whilst I linger here;_</l>
        <l>When hungry, and cold, alas! to my sorrow,</l>
        <l>I cannot forget our soft tack so ligt,</l>
        <l>And to soothe my feelings, I'm forced to borrow,</l>
        <l>And drink in advance, may Rum for the night.</l>
    </lg>
    <figure>Dividing line.</figure>
    <figure>Tent with flaps open and two occupants, in their sleeping bags, sitting up in fright as they are stared at by a polar bear cub.</figure>
    <lg>
        <l>When the light supper and song are o'er</l>
        <l>I sleep, and then dream of my Father's hall,</l>
        <l>But hang it, the snow comes in at the door,</l>
        <l>And the outside man, won't answer my call;_</l>
        <l>Then some Bear, that roams forsaken,</l>
        <l>Should our pemmican smelling in passing along,</l>
        <l>I have only to bawl out "a Bruin" to waken,</l>
        <l>All hand, who frighten him off with a song.</l>
    </lg>
    <figure>Dividing line.</figure>
    <figure>In the foreground, a man in a coat and boots hold up a pot of something steaming. In the background there is the peak of a tent and two shaodwy figures seem to be talking to one another.</figure>
    <lg>
        <l>When at Morn I awake, and with tin pot o'erflowing</l>
        <l>Qith Cocoa_ May fast I break with the rest,</l>
        <l>Counted I feel_ not a sad thought bestowing,</l>
        <l>On privation or care_ but think myself blest;_</l>
        <l>For the cup of pure joy_ I have as a lover,</l>
        <l>Seen filled by my maid, <hi rend="underline">almost</hi> to the brim,</l>
        <l>And whilst I am absent, young Cupid will hover,</l>
        <l>Around me, whilst I prove constant to him</l>
    </lg>
    <signed>C.F. M<hi rend="superscript">c</hi> D.</signed>
    <figure>Dividing line.</figure>
</div>
<div>
    <head>CAPT<hi rend="superscript">N</hi> PENNY'S EXPEDITION.</head>
    <figure>Illuminate letter. Chinese man in a stockade forming the letter 'T'.</figure>
    <p>HE arrival and departure of Captain Penny has been another break in the monotony of the past month_ Our gallant coadjutor<!-- Why whould they have a bishop on board? I could understand a chaplin, but a bishop? -->,arrived on Thursday the 17<hi rend="superscript">th</hi>inst. in his Carriage and eight, from his winter quarters_ a distance of twenty-four miles which he accomplished in four hours + a half.</p>
    <p>He looked as well as his best friend could desire, and brought the gratifying intelligence that the Officers and Crews of the Brigs "Lady Franklin, and Sophia, were in goos health and high spirits, and that the veteran Arctic Navigator_ Sir John Ross, as well as his gallan comrade Captain Phillips, looed forward as cheerfully as the youngest of us to a merry Christmas, and a happy New Year.</p>
    <figure>Arctic landscape with mountains in the background and ice floe in the foreground. Two figures seated in a slead with presumably slead dogs. One figure has his arm raised with whip in hand.</figure><pb/>
</div>
<div>
    <figure>Banner image of an ice floe with mountains in the background. Throughout ther picture there are men on ice, boats, and land aiming in all different firections. There are a few bords on the water, on in particular is center with multiple figures aiming at it.</figure>
    <head>STRAY SHOTS.</head>
    <lg>
        <l>Our great Guns, ought to pay a tribute,</l>
        <l>Unless they porting news contribute_</l>
        <l>Relate dicreetly, what befel</l>
        <l>The ducks and drakes at seventh bell;_</l>
        <l>inform us, what the size of shot</l>
        <l>They used when killing for the pot_</l>
        <l>Whether an old bird chanced to know,</l>
        <l>Men white with Sheets, from heaps of snow</l>
        <l>And if they subterfuge suceeded;</l>
        <l>Or failed, as on the same night, we did_</l>
        <l>Why Mantons did not kill as well</l>
        <l>As those Guns, other makers sell_</l>
        <l>Why at the first discharge there burst</l>
        <l>A Tipping, that seem'd sound at first,</l>
        <l>Why dovekies<note>This is known as the 'little auk' or scientific name Alle alle. Most common in the north Atlantic or arctic.</note> do refuse to die_</l>
        <l>When struck so hard they cannot fly,</l>
        <l>When seemingly they're not alive.</l>
        <l>They quietyly cock tail, and dive,</l>
        <l>Or if the little duck or puffin</l>
        <l>Repay the trouble of a stuffin (g)</l>
        <l>The hour of day, divers<!-- They had divers on this expedition? In the arctic? In the 1850s? Waaaaaaaait, this might be a reference to the birds... --> best see,</l> 
        <l>Their double barrelled enemy_</l>
        <l>Your Ammunition pray display,</l>
        <l>And teach the novices the way</l>
        <l>To scatter shot in right direction,</l>
        <l>Piercing the feathery protection_</l>
        <l>That filled the oldest with surprise,</l>
        <l>Ay! made them doubt their well tried eyes.</l>
        <l>Thus like your lead, you'll scatter round,</l>
        <l>Knowledge by long ecperience found_</l>
        <l>Your Artists then at any rate,</l>
        <l>The "Arctic News" will illustrate</l>
        <l>And as sage Punch can not here roam,</l>
        <l>Supply his places 'till we reach home</l>
    </lg>
    <signed>C. E.</signed>
</div>
<div>
    <figure>Water with mountains in the background. There is a canoe on the watter with a man in it carrying a barrel and other items. In one hand he holds an ore the other is raised above his head with a spear. On the shore ther eis another figure carrying a spear. </figure>
    <head type="main">ESQUIMAUX CANOES.</head>
    <head type="sub">AT THE WHALE FISH ISLANDS.</head>
    <figure>Dividing line.</figure>
    <p>Shortly after anchoring we were surrounded by Esquimaux in their Canoes, which are well worthy of notice, being proofs of the ingenuity + workmanship of the builders.</p>
    <p>They are composed of a light frame work of wood (imported from Denmark) over which Seal skins are sown, rendering the Boat light + buoyant, and quite impervious to water.</p>
    <p>A hole large enough to admit a man's body is left in the centre of the Canoe_ around it is placed a combing of wood, about 2 inches in height_ Over this is drawn the Deer skin frock of the setter, so that the Boat fitted in this manner is quite water tight.</p>
    <p>The implements used for fishing, consist of Spears, and Knives_ the former are tipped with bone, and are thrown in a very desxterous manner by an experienced hand.</p>
    <p>The one used for Seals, is somewhat larger than the others; a small line is fastened to it, and then coiled on a kind of Skeleton drum, (one of the fixtures of the Canoe,) the other end is attached to and inflated Seal skin, which serves to indicate the position of the Seal, which always diver on being wounsws._</p>
    <signed>G. F. M<hi rend="superscript">c</hi> D.</signed> <pb/>
</div>
<div>
    <head>REMEMBRANCE.</head>
    <lg>
        <l>In the wastes of the North, if e'er thou shouldst roam,</l>
        <l>And thy pathway with snow be enwreathed_</l>
        <l>Should the song, and the strain, thou hast once heard at home,</l>
        <l>By the lips of thy messmate be breathed_</l>
        <l>It will come o'er thine ear like a dream of delight,</l>
        <l>Of the scenes of thy youth will remind thee,</l>
        <l>'Twill brighten thy thoughts, and its echo will light,</l>
        <l>The darkness, and shadows round thee.</l>
    </lg>
    <figure> Dividing line.</figure>
    <lg>
        <l>For remembrance is like to the Seasons that roll,</l>
        <l>And run their appointed time_</l>
        <l>For summer departs,_ but paints on the scroll,</l>
        <l>The return of pure joys left behind;_</l>
        <l>Thus, memory will last 'mid the storm and the blast,</l>
        <l>And cheer the wanderer's way</l>
        <l>To his home, he will turn, to think of the past,</l>
        <l>And dream of a future day._</l>
    </lg>
    <figure>Dividing line. </figure>   
</div>
<div>
    <figure><graphic url="TIAN_1_08_a.jpg"/><ab type="caption">"THERE'S A SWEET LITTLE CHERUB THAT SITS UP ALOFT."</ab></figure>
    <figure><graphic url="TIAN_1_08_b.jpg"/></figure> 
    <p>N Monday last Benhamin Balloon, literally inflated himself, from a Cask containing Hydro-Gin_ he became light headed in consequence, and falling into a current of air soon disappeared from the sight of the astonished spectators.</p>
    <p>He is supposed to have on his person, papers to a great amount._ Active steps will be taken for their recovery, they being for the most part,Drafts at sight , on the firm of Mess<hi rend="superscript">rs</hi> Cask and Case, of Cape Hotham, and Leopold Island._</p>
</div>
<div>
    <!-- Griffith's Island, Oct<hi rend="superscript">r</hi> 1850 -->
    <p>H.M.Ships, Resolute, Assistance, Pioneer, + Intrepid, bound westward, admitted to pratigue by the authorities, having brought clean bills of health from Greinhithe_ They intend wintering under the island.</p>
    <p>Homeward bound Fleet not yet hove in sight.</p>
    <figure><graphic url="TIAN_1_08_c.jpg"/><ab type="caption">OH!_ RELEASE ME_OH! RELEASE ME_ OR BY HYDRO YES WITH HYDRO-GIN YOU'LL MAKE ME BURST.</ab></figure><pb/>
</div>
<div>
    <head>OUR PROSPECTS.</head>
    <figure><graphic url="TIAN_1_09_a.jpg"/></figure><p>HE Arctic Winter is fast throwing its mantle over us_ the separting Sun;_ the falling Thermometer, and the decreasing light_ with the sombre aspect of the Sky, and all around betoken that the gloomy + rigid reason is at hand. How do we meet it? Thank God! in good health and Spirits.</p>
    <p>We feel that the glorious cause in which we are engaged, has received our undevided energies + abilities,_ that we have made every possible search, and advanced as far as the state of the season permitted.</p>
    <p>Our labors have been in some measure crowned with sucess. We have found positive traces, + although from the circumstance of no record having been left by our missing Countrymen to mark their track, we are still at fault;_ yet we look forward with bright hope to the future, + trust that the operations of the Spring if they do not lead us to their relief_ will at least enable us to ascertain their fate.</p>
    <p>Our present object is to pass the dismal time before us, as pleasantly as possible;_ + seeing how entirely we depend on each other for amusement to wile away the weary hours, it behoves us all to contribute what we can to the common weal_ and by social intercourse, avert that depression of spirits we should otherwise feel._ Let us also embrace every opportunity of enjoying pure air and proper exercise recollecting how necessary they are to health, and when the delightful Spring bursts upon us_ if we do not rise as Lions refreshed_ we shall in all probability be little the worse, either physically or mentally.</p>
    <p>Although far removed from the society of families, and friends, we are often present with them in throught, at the sweet Village Church_ family Table or participating in the amusement of the domestic Circle, and as_ "Anticipation forward points the view" We delight in the prospect of happier days to come, when we shall again in reality enjoy the blessings of domestic intercourse around the hearths of those we love best.</p>
    <signed>Hope (J.L)</signed>
    <figure>Dividing line.</figure>
</div>
<div>
    <head>STATE OF THE SUN.</head>
    <figure><graphic url="TIAN_1_09_b.jpg"/></figure><p>T is our sad + painful duty, to announce to our Readers, the increasing infirmities of the Arctic Sun._ His state for some days past has been so low as to render him incapable of reaching the summit of Griffith's Island, and the time devoted to daily exersise, is gradually siminishing. There are some who are of opinion that he cannot linger beyond the second week of the ensuing month.</p>
    <p>Alas! we remember him a short time since, the light of the Season, the brightest luminary of the Arctic world_ the observed of all observers, and his endurance so great, as to be able to dispense with rest for months.</p>
    <p>Although we do not claim the gift of prophecy, we foretold his fall, but were among those who sincerely regretted it. Even after it became apparent that he was sinking rapidly, he for some time obstinately refused to try the effects of sea bathing.</p><pb/>
    <p><!-- Start using the Hamilton copy here. -->There are those who despair of his recovery in consequence of his increasing declination. We however his professional attendants think differently, being in our own minds confident his declination is decreasing and on that we found our hopes, that with returning Spring, he will again be restored to us, and we trist that all our Readers will live to enjoy in health and happiness the enlivening influence of his delightful presence.</p>
    <signed>G.F. M<hi rend="superscript">C</hi>D.</signed>
    <figure>Dividing line.</figure>
</div>
<div>
    <head>ARCTIC DRAMA ADVERTISEMENT.</head>
    <figure>Small dividing line.</figure>
    <p>The managers &amp; Company of the Royal Arctic Theatre, beg to announce their intention of commencing their performances on board H.M.S. "Assistance" on Saturday the 9<hi rend="superscript">th</hi> Nov<hi rend="superscript">r</hi> 1850, in honor of the anniversary of the birth of H.R.H the Prince of Wales._ On which occasion the Captain and Officers will perform the Farce of "Married Life" or "Did you ever send your wife to Camberwell?"__</p>
    <p>The Entertainment will conclude with the Farce of the "Lottery Ticket" to be performed by the Ship's Company.</p>
    <p>The Manager trusts that the attention which has been bestowed on the magnificent Senery, Decorations, + Dresses, will be fully rewarded by the approbation of his numerous patrons, + an Arctic Public.</p>
    <p>He also takes this oppotunity of returning his best thanks to that eminent Artist, Lieut: Browne for, his valuable contributions to the Scenery.</p>
</div>
<div>
    <figure>Small dividing line.</figure>
    <head>SHAKINGS.</head>
    <p>A good Pioneer must be a Resolute man. Few men however Intrepid, but have felt the want of Assistance.</p>
</div>
<div>
    <figure>Small dividing line.</figure>
    <head>CONUNDRUMS.</head>
    <p>Q._ Why should we in our present position be considered very knowing?</p>
    <p>A._ Because there's nothing gree about us._</p>
    <p>Q._ Why are Parhelia like Indian Hunting Boots?</p>
    <p>A._ Because they are mock-suns (moccasins.)</p>
</div>
<div>
    <lg>
        <l>Opening of the</l>
        <l>Royal Arctic Theatre.</l>
        <l>H.M.S. ASSISTANCE,</l>
        <l>In honor of the birthday of H. R. H.</l>
        <l>the Prince of Wales</l>
    </lg>
    <figure>Small dividing line.</figure>
    <p>Manager._ Capt<hi rend="superscript">n</hi> Ommanney</p>
    <figure>Dividing line.</figure>
    <p>Under the patronage of Capt<hi rend="superscript">n</hi> Hor Austin, C<gap reason="indecipherable" quantity="2" unit="characters"/></p>
    <figure>Fancy dividing line.</figure>
    <lg>
        <l>On Saturday the 9<hi rend="superscript">th</hi> Nov<hi rend="superscript">r</hi> 1850;</l>
        <l>will be performed by the Captain &amp; Officers,</l>
        <l>The populat laughable Farce of</l>
        <l>MARRIED LIFE!</l>
        <l>or</l>
        <l>DID YOU EVER SEND YOUR WIDE TO CAMBERWELL?</l>
    </lg>
    <figure>Dividing line.</figure>
    <p>After which Several Cominc Songs, and the Orchestra will perform some of the most select Pieces!</p>
    <figure>Dividing line.</figure>
    <p>THe whole to conclude with the much admored Farce of</p>
    <lg>
        <l>THE</l>
        <l>LOTTERY TICKET!</l>
        <l>Which will be performed by the Ship's Company, and embraces scenes of great interest!!</l>
    </lg>
    <figure>Dividing line.</figure>
    <p>The Scenery has been prepared by the most eminent artists; and together with the Dressers are on a scale of unrivalled magnificence!</p>
    <p>A splendid Drop Scene by Lieut Browne!</p>
    <figure>Dividing line.</figure>
    <p>Doors open at 6 o'Clock. ___ Commence at 6.30.</p>
    <p>The Police are directed to take in charge all disorderly Women + dogs.</p>
    <figure>Dividing line.</figure>
    <p>F.J.K. Printer</p>
</div>
<div>
    <p>It were needless to attempt excuses for the many defects of this our first number._ an an equally hopless task to explain our heartfelt thanks to our many kind contributors.</p>
    <p>Trusting therefore to the generous critisim of the Squadron we shall give the printer's Devil a holiday, and drink sucess to the "Illustrated Arctic News".__ (Editors.)</p>
    <figure><graphic url="TIAN_1_10_a.jpg"/></figure><pb/>
</div>
</div>